Cole Abidemi

Fullstack Developer

Minna, Niger State

LinkedIn | GitHub | Email | +2348138025345

An experienced Full-stack Developer with 9 years of experience in developing and maintaining complex web applications. Passionate about writing clean code that is reusable & follows the DRY principle. Designs interfaces that incorporate accessibility & user-friendliness. Approaches all new projects with the priorities of simplicity and functionality.

Technical Skills

- Programming languages: JavaScript, Python, PHP, C#.
- Front-end frameworks and technologies: Vue.js, HTML, CSS, Tailwindcss, Bootstrap, Primevue, vuetify.
- Back-end frameworks and technologies: Node.js, Laravel, Inertiajs, Core PHP, Django, Express.
- Database management: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase.
- Version control systems: Git, GitHub, BitBucket
- Deployment tools: Docker, AWS.
- Testing frameworks: Jest, PHPUnit.
- Development methodologies: Agile, Scrum.
- Other relevant technologies: REST APIs, Redis.

Web Development Projects

E- Wallet Application: Back-End/Front-End Project | https://gogenterprises.com/

- Delivered an E-wallet App using Laravel, Inertiajs, and MySQL that allows users to register, login, and perform various operations. e.g. buying of recharge cards, Data subscription, TV subscription, Money withdrawal and Transfer
- Added a custom restricted middleware to prevent access to unauthorized endpoints.
- Tested with phpunit unit testing.

Education

Computer Science /Higher National Diploma (HND) Federal Polytechnic Offa, Kwara state. Nigeria 2014 - 2020

React crash course/Certification Pirple school - online 2022

Server Administration/Certification Pirple school - online

The Internet Web Development 2015

After I finished my college education, I started exploring the internet for more and better education in the world of web development.

I started watching videos and taught myself, thanks to some of the best video tutorial websites like:

- Laracasts (https://laracasts.com/)
- Pluralsight (http://pluralsight.com/)
- Code School (https://www.codeschool.com/)
- Vue School (https://vueschool.io/)

and a few more.

I've also learned a lot from different blogs, conference talk videos, podcasts, books and other sources which provide information about web development.

I am also active on the various PHP/Laravel/JavaScript/VueJS/TailwindCSS forums and community chat channels on Slack and Discord.

Recent Work Experience

I.T. Instructor, NYSC SAED, Inc June 2021 – July 2023

- Teach HTML, CSS, Javascript.
- Teach Data analysis using Excel.

Full-Stack Developer, GOG, Inc.

October 2021 - march 2022

- Led the development of a new e-Wallet platform using Laravel, Inertiajs, and MySQL.
- Designed and developed the platform's back-end architecture, including the database schema and APIs.
- Implemented the front-end using Inertiajs and Tailwind CSS, ensuring a smooth user experience and intuitive design.
- Collaborated with the product team to ensure the platform meets the business requirements and user needs.
- Integrated the platform with various third-party APIs, including payment gateways and authentication providers.
- Conducted regular maintenance and updates to ensure the website is secure and up-to-date with the latest technologies.
- Hosted the application on a share hosting platform, using Git to manage the deployment process.
- Configured the server environment to ensure the application runs smoothly and is accessible to the public.

Frontend Developer, JDLab

December 2022 - January 2024

- Developed and maintained web applications using Vue.js and Pinia for state management.
- Integrated third-party APIs and libraries using Vue.js composition API plugins.
- Developed reusable UI components using styled-components to ensure consistency and maintainability.
- Enhanced user experience by implementing performance optimizations, reducing page load times by 20%.
- Collaborated with designers and backend developers to ensure seamless integration of front-end and back-end functionality.
- Conducted code reviews and provided constructive feedback to team members on Vue.js code.
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings and provided updates on project progress.

Frontend Developer, UBT Consults

June 2024

- Developed and maintained web applications using Vue.js and Pinia for state management
- Integrated third-party APIs and libraries using Vue.js composition API plugins
- Developed reusable UI components using styled-components to ensure consistency and maintainability.
- Collaborated with designers and backend developers to ensure seamless integration of front-end and back-end functionality
- Conducted code reviews and provided constructive feedback to team members on Vue.is code
- Mentored junior developers, helping them improve their skills and understanding of Vue.is.
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings and provided updates on project progress